# Luong-Ha Nguyen

Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning Engineer

Experienced AI/ML Engineer with a background in developing and optimizing learning paradigms as well as AI/ML pipelines, including modeling, validation, and deployment strategies in production. Skilled in uncertainty modeling and machine learning approaches, with a notable track record in driving innovation in manufacturing, renewable energy, infrastructure monitoring, and aerospace sectors through interdisciplinary teamwork.

(hazone.me

github.com/lhnguyen102

in linkedin.com/in/luong-ha-nguyen-697941b4

◆ +1 (438) 928-2616 ■ luongha.nguyen@gmail.com • Montreal, QC, CANADA

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Machine Learning Engineer at AI Redefined | Montreal, QC, CA

July, 2022 - present

- Develop end-to-end machine learning pipelines for time series forecasting and anomaly detection, using reinforcement learning with human feedback to continually enhance accuracy through insights from operators and asset managers.
- Lead the development of vision-based detection algorithms using reinforcement learning with human feedback.
- Collaborate on targeted research projects with key industrial and academic partners for field innovation.

## Applied Research Associate at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

May, 2022 - presen

- Lead and coordinate a team of PhDs and postdocs to develop an AI/ML framework, optimizing accuracy and reducing training time in deep neural networks, paving the way for major advancements in various industries.
- Lead the technical development of open-source software for Bayesian neural networks cuTAGI.
- Lead the technical development of Python interface for integration with the C++/CUDA backend.

Machine Learning Engineer at Shearwater Aerospace | Montreal, QC, CA

September, 2021 - June, 2022

- Developed machine learning-based path planning system to improve UAV flight efficiency.
- Developed an autonomous control system using reinforcement learning for UAVs.

Postdoctoral Researcher at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

November, 2019 - September, 2021

- Developed a theory-based approach for modeling uncertainty in deep neural networks, enhancing reliability.
- Implemented and tested the proposed approach on supervised, unsupervised, and reinforcement learning tasks.

# **SKILLS**

Tech Stack

C/C++ CUDA Python MATLAB JavaScript React Terraform AWS Azure Cloud Computing

Microservices gRPC REST API Kubernetes PostgreSQL Docker GitHub Helm Charts

AI/ML

PyTorch TensorFlow Numpy Pandas Scikit-learn Probability & Statistics Reinforcement Learning

Machine Learning Theories Supervised Leanring Unsupervised Leanring

Languages Fluent in English and French, with native proficiency in Vietnamese

### **EDUCATION**

Ph.D. in Computer Science for Civil Engineering at Polytechnique Montreal | Montreal, QC, CA

October, 2019

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

cuTAGI for Bayesian Neural Networks (2018-present) | tagiml.com

- cuTAGI: An open-source Bayesian neural network developed in C++/CUDA. It quantifies uncertainty in deep neural networks for various learning tasks, enhancing output reliability and accuracy.

Transformer Temporal Fusion (2023) | Source code: github.com/lhnguyen102/tft-sgd

- Implementation of the Transformer Temporal Fusion (TFT) method, leveraging self-attention mechanisms for enhanced accuracy and detailed explainability in time series forecasting.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Analytically Tractable Hidden-States Inference in Bayesian Neural Networks. JMLR, 2022.
- 2. Tractable Approximate Gaussian Inference for Bayesian Neural Networks. JMLR, 2021.
- 3. Analytically Tractable Inference in Neural Networks-An Alternative to Backpropagation, NeurIPS, 2021.